Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jianyang-8500692 (LinkedIn) citation.webibooth.com (Personal) bible.webibooth.com (Personal) finance.webibooth.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Python (Programming Language) C++

Django

Certifications

Applied Data Science Program

Hackathon- The Hack Linguist 9th
position

Jian Yang

Freelancer Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer Penfield, New York, United States

Summary

Data science professional with expertise in machine learning, artificial intelligence, data mining, data processing, and storytelling; having extensive experience in programming and quantitative modeling to support the whole life-cycle of the machine model design and implementation.

Skills:

- PROGRAMMING: Python, C++, C#, Database, SQL, JQuery, JavaScript, Django, d3.js
- MACHINE LEARNING: PCA, clustering, classification, regression, deep learning, etc.
- MATH: linear algebra, calculus, probability, descriptive statistics, hypothesis testing, Fourier analysis, predictive modelling, signal detection theory.
- PYTHON LIBRARIES: pandas, numpy, scipy, sklearn, tensorflow, matplotlib, seaborn, ploty, jupyter.

Experience

Owl Autonomous Imaging
Consulting Image and Optical Scientist
August 2022 - Present (9 months)
Fairport, New York, United States

Image processing and Machine learning related to autonomous driving technology.

The Gleason Works
Sr. Software Engineer
January 2008 - March 2021 (13 years 3 months)
Rochester, New York

 Quoted, designed, and implemented software features on the company's commercial gear testing machines based on customer orders and internal needs, using C++/C#. The areas include human machine interface, machine process control, network communication, analysis of recorded data in time series and Fourier domain, data storage, and information visualization.

- Support customers (motor vehicle manufactures and supplies) and field engineers in trouble shooting machine functions via phone, email, and online web tools.
- Designed and implemented Python Django websites and C++/C# and WPF applications to improve work processes, and for software testing and upgrading.

Storm Frog, Inc
.Net Web Developer
January 2007 - December 2007 (1 year)
Victor, New York

Worked on web content management systems.

Eastman Kodak Company
Principal Image Scientist
August 1998 - June 2005 (6 years 11 months)
Rochester, New York

Conducted research and development, applying visual perception technology in image product design.

University of Houston Research Associate November 1995 - July 1998 (2 years 9 months) Houston, Texas, United States

Designed and conducted psychophysical experiments on stereopsis, eye movement, motion perception and light adaptation. Created spatially and temporally varying patterns on video displays to run experiments.

University of Rochester
Postdoctoral Fellow
May 1991 - October 1995 (4 years 6 months)
Rochester, New York, United States

Developed quantitative models of human visual perception

Schepens Eye Research Institute Research Assistant 1989 - 1990 (1 year) Boston, Massachusetts, United States

Conducted psychophysical experiments and vision-based image processing

Education

Northeastern University
PHD, Experimental Psychology · (1991)

Shanghai Institute of Optics & Fine Mechanics MS, Optics · (1984)

Fudan University BS, Physics · (1982)